OVERVIEW

I am seeking employment as a web site and web application Developer.

I have over thirteen years full-time experience in web development, and have been writing computer programs sporadically for the last twenty-five years. Additionally I have a strong knowledge of databases including Microsoft Access, SQL Server and SAS. I am skilled in Transact SQL including the writing of stored procedures. I am an expert at programming web sites and web applications using the Microsoft ASP and ASP.NET technologies. I've been using Microsoft Visual Studio.Net since 2002 to develop web applications in ASP.NET. In developing ASP and ASP.NET sites, my scripting languages of choice are server-side VB Script (for ASP) and C# (for ASP.NET), along with client-side JavaScript and AJAX. Programming for the Internet has made me comfortable and familiar with IIS. My preferred database application is SQL Server. I am experienced at normalizing databases.

I have developed or improved web sites and web applications for the Internal Revenue Service, Overseas Private Investment Corporation, Veterans Affairs, Navy (Cormis & FFSMIS), Institute of International Finance, DC Government, Nature's Sunshine Products, Neways International, Airline Pilots Association, and numerous other private and government agencies.

Training and mentoring others in the latest technologies is something I enjoy. I've taught several training lessons on ASP, as well as an in-depth, four month long SQL Server class. While at InterImage, I lead a MSDN training course entitle "Upgrading Web Development Skills from ASP to Microsoft ASP.NET". Most recently, I wrote and taught training course on HTML and CSS. I am familiar with web services. I also have a good eye for colors and design, and I often do graphic design using Adobe PhotoShop.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS

COMPUTER PROGRAMMING

e
)6
e
e
e
e
e
e
e
e
)5
000
e
2003
e
1999

H. Walter VanderHeide – 86 E. 1450 S., Orem, Utah. 801.226.0952

vanman798@yahoo.com

SOFTWARE – VISUAL STUDIO (with Team Foundation Server), OFFICE (which includes ACCESS, WORD, EXCEL, and POWERPOINT), SQL SERVER 2008 (including stored procedures), IBM INFORMIX (via Server Studio, or WINSQL), PHOTOSHOP, ACROBAT, and IIS.

OTHER SKILLS -- Trained in formal logic, calculus, differential equations, linear algebra, probability theory, regression analysis, hypothesis testing, quality control, physics, and economics. Accomplished in analysis and interpretation of statistical data; summarization and presentation of data in narrative, tabular, or graphical form. Experienced and comfortable working with the public. Three years experience living overseas. Completed one-year, hands-on, and class room lead, management training course.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Applications Developer, Neways, Springville, UT – June 2011 – present

- Develop Object-Oriented Internet-based web applications using ASP.NET (with C#), ADO.NET, XML, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, JQuery and SQL (Informix). See http://www.neways.com.
- Design normalized relational databases.
- Write stored procedures for IBM Informix database, and SQL Server.
- Develop web forms, user controls, and web services.
- Write new code, modify existing code, found and repaired bugs.
- Create modules for Telerik Site Finity content management platform.

Senior Internet Developer, Nature's Sunshine Products, Provo, UT - February 2006 - November 2010

- Developed Object-Oriented Internet-based web applications using ASP.NET (with C#), ADO.NET, XML, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, AJAX, JQuery, web-services, and SQL. See http://www.natr.com.
- Designed normalized relational databases.
- Wrote stored procedures.
- Developed web forms, user controls, and web services.
- Wrote new code, modify existing code, found and repaired bugs.

Software Engineer, Net Endeavor., Pleasant Grove, UT – August 2005 – February 2006

- Developed Object-Oriented Internet-based web applications using ASP.NET (with C#), ADO.NET, XML, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and SQL.
- Designed normalized relational databases.
- Wrote stored procedures.
- Developed web forms, and user controls.
- Wrote new code, modify existing code, found and repaired bugs.
- Performed code reviews on other developer's work.
- Developed and designed reports using SQL Reporting Services.

Web Application Developer, Air Line Pilots Association, Intl., Herdnon VA - April 2004 – August 2005

- Developed Internet/Intranet web applications, web sites, and web services with ASP.NET (with VB.NET and/or C#), ADO.NET, XML, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and SQL (including stored procedures). See https://crewroom.alpa.org, https://crewroom.alpa.org, https://crewroom.alpa.org/ualri/Default.aspx.
- Developed custom modules for use with the DotNetNuke open source portal product, in ASP.NET.
- Designed Interface Prototypes including creating graphics using Adobe PhotoShop, and skins for DotNetNuke.
- Designed the "look and feel" of new sites, and made improvements to existing sites.
- Assisted and trained other developers.
- Designed normalized relational databases.

H. Walter VanderHeide – 86 E. 1450 S., Orem, Utah. 801.226.0952

vanman798@yahoo.com

- Wrote SQL Server DTS scripts to transfer and transform data from flat files to SQL Server tables. For
 example the data for http://www.alpa.org/fdx/jumpseat/ is transferred from a flat file to SQL via DTS.
- Led projects through the whole development lifecycle (from concept, through development, to installation).

Web Application Developer, InterImage, Inc., Arlington VA - February 2000 – April 2004

- Developed Internet/Intranet web applications and web sites using these technologies: ASP.NET (with VB.NET and/or C#), ADO.NET, ASP (with VBScript), XML, JavaScript, ADO, SQL (including stored procedures), COM, ActiveX, and Web Services.
- Designed and maintained relational databases. Expert with Microsoft SQL Server and Microsoft Access.
- Daily, wrote ASP, ASP.NET, JavaScript, VBScript, HTML (raw code), DHTML, SQL (including stored procedures), and CSS for new web sites and for maintenance to existing sites.
- Developed COM servers for use with MTS.
- Lead projects through the whole development lifecycle (from concept, through development, to installation).
- Designed the "look and feel" of new sites, and made improvements to existing sites.
- Created Interface prototypes including creating graphics using Adobe PhotoShop, Macromedia Fireworks, and Flash.
- Did Intranet contract work for several government agencies as the primary representative of InterImage.
- Set up site-specific search engines using index server.
- Functioned as a *Technical Lead*, by managing the technical side of projects.
- Assisted and trained other developers.
- Interviewed job seekers.

Web Master/Economist, Bureau of Labor Statistics, Washington, DC - August 1997 to February 2000

- Wrote HTML for updates and improvements to the Consumer Expenditure Survey web site (http://www.bls.gov/cex/).
- Designed, programmed, and maintain an Intranet that improved the storage and retrieval of data tables.
- Trained fellow employees in use of UNIX operating system.
- Wrote SAS programs (including ANSI SQL) to extract, analyze, and group data from a database.
- Prepared interpretations of price data in narrative, graphical, and/or tabular forms using Microsoft Office products.
- Analyzed expenditure data and calculated descriptive statistics.
- Wrote data documentation for both public-use data and in-house data.
- Researched consumer expenditure topics (published in the September 1999 <u>Monthly Labor Review</u>, see http://stats.bls.gov/opub/mlr/1999/09/atissue.htm).
- Volunteered as a college recruiter doing both informational job fairs, and interviewing.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science - 1992; Brigham Young University; Provo, Utah. On going computer training classes from various schools and training centers; over 19-computer or web development related courses completed since 1998. Attended Dev Connections in 2007, and 2010.